你是做什麼的
So, what do you do?
我在上課  想當個演員
I'm studying to be an actress.
你呢
You?
我是個碼頭工人
I'm a longshoreman.
我是說真的
No, I mean really.
我...我也是說真的
I mean... I mean really too.
不過從下週一開始
Although, starting next Monday,
我要做點兒更棒的事了
I'm doing something a little more glamorous.
什麼
What's that?
自助餐廳的夜班收銀員
Night cashier at a cafeteria.
我不是問你怎麼賺錢
I don't mean how you make money.
我是問
I mean,
你對什麼感興趣
What are you interested in?
親愛的  我要是有這答案
Honey, if I had the answer to that one,
我打賭不出半個小時咱倆都得無聊死
I bet I'd bore us both to death in half an hour.
謝天謝地  終於完了...
Thank God, that's over...
有很多明星都是初次亮相啊
So much for the debut of the laurel players.
她太讓人失望了
...And she was very disappointing.
弗蘭克
Oh, Frank!
太棒了  弗蘭克
Oh, very nice Frank!
謝謝你捧場  吉明斯夫人
Oh, thanks so much, Mrs. Givings.
我們真是太喜歡了
I can't tell you how much we enjoyed it.
你太太真有天賦
You have a very talented wife.
我會轉達的
I'll pass it along!
弗蘭克
Frank!
她在那邊...
She's in there...!
我等不及要喝一杯了
I'm about ready for that drink.
稍等一下
Couple of minutes!
愛寶?
April...?
寶貝兒?
Sweetheart...?
-準備好走了嗎  -好的  好的
-You about ready to leave?  -Yeah, yeah.
我正要卸妝
I've just got to get this makeup off.
那個...我猜
Well... I guess  it wasn't
不是很成功吧
A triumph or anything, was it?
我覺得是
I guess not.
我一會兒就好
I'll be ready in a minute.
不用著急
Take your time.
幫個忙好吧
Listen, will you do me a favor?
米莉和謝普想約我們出去
Milly and Shep wanted us to go out with them after.
你能不能回絕了?
Will you say we can't?
就說保姆要下班什麼的
Say it's because of the baby sitter or something?
可是  我已經答應了
Well, the thing is, I already said that we could.
我...
I mean...
我剛才已經答應他們了
I just saw them and I said we would.
那你能否再出去一趟說剛才搞錯了呢
Then would you mind going out again and saying you were mistaken?
這應該不難吧
That should be simple enough.
你不覺得這有點不禮貌嗎  愛寶
Don't you think that's a little bit rude, April?
好吧  我自己去說
Well I'll tell them myself.
好
Okay.
好  別急
Okay. Take it easy.
好吧
All right?
我去說
I'll tell them.
說真的  寶貝兒
I mean it, baby.
你是這戲裡唯一的亮點
You were the only person in that play.
謝謝
Thank you.
就不該讓你搞這破戲劇  這是關鍵
We should've let you get mixed up in the damned thing. It's all.
行了
All right.
一幫業餘的傢伙
A bunch of amateurs.
我是說  你可是科班出身
I mean, you've studied for Christ's sake.
能別嘮叨了嗎
Could we stop talking about it now?
好
Sure.
我只是不想讓你太難過
I just don't want you feeling bad about it, that's all,
太不值得了
Because it's not worth it, you know?
-和這幫鳥人生活在這兒就夠憋屈了  -是
-It's bad enough having to live out here among these damn people -Yes.
-你說什麼  -我說"是"  弗蘭克
-What'd you say?  -I said yes. All right, Frank.
能別再說這個了嗎
Could you just stop talking about it now,
免得把我逼瘋
Before you drive me crazy, please?
你幹嗎
What are you doing?
愛寶
April...
親愛的
Sweetheart...
我們該談談
Let's talk about this, okay?
拜託  我不想談
Please, don't do that.
來
Come on now.
別碰我
Don't touch me.
愛寶  愛寶
April... April...
離我遠點兒
You just... Leave me alone!
好
Okay.
我受夠了  這一堆狗屁爛事兒
It strikes me, that there's a considerable amount of bullshit...
這裡
Going on here,
我只想澄清幾件事
and there is just a few things, that I'd like to clear up.
好吧
All right?
第一
Number one:
這劇這麼噁心不是我的錯
It's not my fault the play was lousy.
第二
Number two:
你沒當成真正的演員
It's sure as hell not my fault
也他媽不是我的錯
That you didn't turn out to be an actress,
還有  你越快忘記那些肥皂劇
And the sooner you get over that little piece of soap opera
我們就能過得越好
The better off we'll both be.
第三
Number three:
我不是那種
I don't happen to fit the role
木訥遲鈍的鄉下漢子
of dumb, insensitive suburban husband,
自從我們搬來這裡  你就一直想讓我變成那樣
You've been trying to leave that crap on me ever since we moved out here.
我受夠了
And I'm damn before wear.
第四
Number four:
愛寶
April...
April!
愛寶
April...
你到底要幹嗎  快回來
What the hell are you doing? Get back to the car.
不  我一會兒回去
No. I will in a minute
讓我在這站會兒
Just let me stand here for a second.
媽的
Goddamnit.
愛寶
April...
你能不能回到車裡  我們好好談
Can you please, just get back in the car, and talk about this,
別在12號國道上亂跑好嗎
Instead of running all over Route 12?
我說得不夠清楚嗎  我不想談
Haven't I made it clear I don't particularly want to talk about it?
好吧  看在老天的份上
Okay. I mean, Jesus, I'm trying to be nice
我很想好好談談
about this thing. For God's sake.
你可真體貼
How kind of you.
太他媽的體貼了
How terribly, terribly kind of you.
等等  我做錯什麼啦
Wait a minute. I don't deserve this.
你總是這麼絕對地說
You're always so wonderfully definite, on the subject of...
-你該怎樣不該怎樣  -等等
-What you do and don't deserve? -Wait a minute!
媽的  等等
Wait a goddamn...
愛寶  現在你聽我說
April, now you listen to me.
這一次
This is one time
你別想再曲解我的話  愛寶
You're not gonna get away with twisting everything that I say, April.
就這一次
This just happen to be one goddamn time.
我知道  我沒錯
I know I'm not the wrong here.
天哪  我真希望你今天沒來
Christ, I wish you'd stayed home tonight!
你知道現在的你怎麼了嗎  愛寶
You know what you are, when you are like this, April?
你有病
You're sick.
沒錯
I really mean that.
就是有病
You're sick!
-你知道你又怎麼了嗎  -怎麼
-And you know what you are? -What?
-你很噁心  -是嗎
-You're disgusting. -Oh yeah?
你別唬我  弗蘭克
You don't bully me, Frank.
就因為你把我困在這個安全的小陷阱裡
Just because you've got me safely in this little trap,
你以為你就能強迫我去感受你的感受嗎
You think you can bully me into feeling whatever you want!
-陷阱  你說這是陷阱  -是  就是
-In a trap! You in a trap! -Yeah. Yeah.
-天哪  -我  弗蘭克  我
-Jesus! -Me, Frank. Me!
笑死我了
Don't make me laugh.
你這個可憐的自欺欺人的臭小子  看看你
You pathetic, self-deluded little boy. Look at you!
看看你
Look at you!
好好看看你自己再告訴我
Look at you and tell me,
你哪來的那麼多想像力
How by any stretch of the imagination
管自己叫男人
You can call yourself a man!
操
Fuck!
媽的
Damn!
上帝啊
Oh, Jesus Christ!
別這麼看著我  愛寶
Don't look at me like that, April.
我們能回家了嗎
Could we please go home now?
革命之路
15層到了
Fifteenth floor.
老弟  今天你得幫幫我
I'm going to need your help this morning, Old Scout.
一會兒要是邦迪過來了  就馬上告訴我
For the next few hours, you're to warn me of Bandy's every approach
還有  別讓大家看見我
And you may need to shield me from public view in the likely event
胃疼的樣子
That avoid my stomach.
太難受了
It's that bad.
早  傑克
Morning, Jack.
看著吧  沒啥好事兒
Nothing good about it, I assure you.
你們一下火車我就知道你們要
Of course, I knew the moment you stepped off the train
找什麼
what you were looking for...
一小間改造穀倉或馬車庫房
A small remodeled barn, or a carriage house.
不過我得告訴你們
And I just hate to be the one to tell you
那種房子已經沒有了
That sort of thing just isn't available anymore...
不過別失望
But I don't want you to despair.
我要帶你們看個地方
There is one place up here I wanna show you...
這裡現在看起來是不怎麼樣
Now of course it isn't very desirable at this end.
你看  克勞福德路上的房子
As you see, Crawford Road is mostly these little
都是很小的煤磚房  像個拖車屋
Cinder-blocky, pick-up trucky places.
住著水管工
Plumbers, carpenters,
木匠之類的當地人
little local people of that sort.
但是...
But eventually...
與它相連的革命路
Eventually it leads up to Revolutionary Road,
狀況可就大相逕庭了
Which is much nicer.
我要帶你們去的  是一幢漂亮的小房子
Now, the place I want to show you, is a sweet little house
佈局很別緻
And a sweet little setting.
簡約清新的設計
Simple, clean lines,
有片很棒的草地  對孩子再合適不過了
Good lawns, marvelous for children.
就在前面的拐角處
It's just around this next curve...
你們馬上就要看到了
Now, you'll see it.
就是那兒
There.
看見那個白色的房子了嗎
See the little white one?
很討人喜歡吧
Sweet, isn't it?
看它神氣活現地佇立在小斜坡上
The perky way it sits there on its little slope?
很迷人吧
Charming, isn't it?
是啊
Oh, yes.
你找我?
You wanted to see me?
這是今天早晨從托萊多寄來的
Came for you from Toledo this morning.
這個月第3份了
This is the third one this month.
-抱歉  我已經很謹慎了...
-Sorry. I thought I'd taken care...
-我本以為
-I'm not prepared to have this...
不會再發生類似事情了  弗蘭克  明白嗎
This conversation again, Frank. You understand?
-我只是...
-I was literaly just getttin...
-週邊的其他分公司都很敬重我們
-These folks in the provinces look up to us.
我們得有效率
We need to be efficient.
我們不能總這麼反覆出錯
We can't have this kind of back and forth, and so forth.
太沒效率了
It's just not efficient.
我說的對吧
Am I Right?
完全正確
Yes.
怎麼了
What was that about?
托萊多
Toledo.
分店經理想要份
Branch manager wants a revised brochure
改好的諾克斯500會議的宣傳冊
For the conference on the Knox 500.
太沒效率了  我說的對吧  對吧  對吧
It's just not efficient. Am I right? Am I right? Am I right?
娘娘腔
Sounds like a goodie.
說實話  我都不知道諾克斯500是什麼
For God's sake. I don't even know what the Knox 500 does...
你知道嗎
Do you?
你以為都跟你似的
Don't insult me.
如果要找SP-1109下的待用文件
If you'll look in the inactive file under SP-1109.
你就能找著所有發給代理商的文件備份
You'll find copies of all the stuff we sent to the agency.
這樣我們就能追蹤到
And that way we can trace the thing back to its...
原始資料
To its original sources.
你午飯不會吃得太早吧
Listen. I hope you weren't planning on an early lunch.
不會
No.
我不太餓
I'm not really hungry.
好  我一會兒再過來
Good. I'll check on you later. All right?
好的
Okay.
好
你知道嗎  莫林
You know something, Maureen?
碰上我算你走運
You're lucky you met me.
怎麼說
Oh? How's that?
我能支你幾招
I think I can show you the ropes, you know.
在諾克斯生存的技巧
There's certain art to survival at Knox.
真的呀?
Really.
瞧著點兒
Let me show you what I mean.
服務生
Waiter.
把電話機拿來好嗎  再來兩杯馬提尼
Bring me the telephone would you? And two more Martinis.
請接克朗代克區55566  謝謝
Klondike 55566, please.
您好  喬根森夫人
Hello Mrs. Jorgensen.
我是弗蘭克·惠勒
Frank Wheeler here.
是的
Yes.
我想跟您說一聲
I just wanted to let you know,
我把莫林·格魯布派到
That I've had to send Maureen Grube
視覺輔助部辦點事兒
Down to Visual Aides for me.
恐怕這一下午她都得留下幫忙
I'll probably need her the rest of the afternoon.
好的
Yes.
您也是
You too.
再見
Take care now.
我都沒聽說過什麼視覺輔助
I've never even heard of Visual Aides.
那是因為...
That's because...
它壓根不存在
It doesn't exist.
你好  海倫
Hi, Helen.
快進來
Come on in.
我不久留了...
Oh, I can't stay a minute...
我就是來送這個景天草盆栽的
I just wanted to bring this sedum plantings
你能用它裝扮前院那小片凌亂的草地
For that messy patch down by the front yard.
就像歐洲石蓮花
It's like the European houseleek
它能開出可愛的小黃花
Only these have the most marvelous little yellow blossoms.
只要在開始的幾天澆上一點水
Now all it wants for the first few day is just a tiny dollop of water
它就能開得生機盎然
And you'll find it absolutely thrives.
太感謝你了  海倫  你太熱心了
Oh. Thank you, Helen. It's so kind of you.
要喝咖啡嗎
Would you like some coffee?
有什麼需要幫忙的嗎  海倫
Is there something I can do for you, Helen?
我差點兒忘了
Oh... I almost forgot.
我有點小事相求
There's a small favor I'd like to ask...
就關於...
It's about...
關於我兒子約翰的
It's about my son, John.
他住院了
He's been in the hospital.
真抱歉  他還好吧
Oh, I'm sorry. Is everything all right?
其實...
Well, actualy...
只是暫時的  他在布魯克醫院
It's just for the time being. He's in... Pleasent Brook.
是精神病院
Psychiatric.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
不嚴重
Oh... Nothing serious.
他只是有點抑鬱
He's just got a little run down.
總有一天會好起來的
Things can just get the better of us sometimes.
你說是吧
Don't you agree?
是的
Yes.
當然
Of course.
那裡設施很不錯
It's a marvellous facility.
治療也挺有效
And the treatments seem to be doing wonders for him...
不過  醫生說讓他出來放鬆一個下午
Anyway, they said getting out for an afternoon
可能對他有好處
Might do him a little bit good.
說實話  他覺得我的朋友都太保守了
I think he finds my friends a little conventional, quite frankly
我是說  他一直離家在外
I mean, he's travelled.
他是數學博士
He has a PhD in mathematics.
說他是個天才也不為過
I suppose you could say he's an intellectual.
讓他和你們這樣的年輕夫婦接觸
It would do him a world of good
會對他幫助很大的
To meet a young couple like you.
我們很高興認識他
We'd love to meet him.
真的?
Really?
是啊
Yes.
我們非常樂意
We'd love to.
謝謝你  親愛的
Thank you, dear.
謝謝
Thank you.
那個...
Well...
我得走了
I must be off.
我還記得你下火車那天的樣子
I remember the first day you came off the train.
你不像其他客戶
You weren't like my other clients.
你與眾不同
You were different.
你看上去...
You just seemed...
很特別
Special...
現在依然是
Of course you still are.
記得哦...
Remember...
澆一點兒水  我得趕緊走了  再見
Just a dollop. I must scoot. Toodle-oo.
再見
Bye.
你讓我醉醺醺的
I think you got me a little drunk.
知道今天什麼日子嗎
You know what today is?
不是星期一嗎
...Monday?
是我生日
It's my birthday.
我今天30歲了
I'm thirty years old today.
生日快樂
Happy birthday!
謝謝
Thank you.
你瞎編的那個部門
What was the name of that, um...
叫什麼來著
Department you made up again?
視覺輔助
Visual Aides.
太逗了
...What-a-joke.
What-a-joke.
天啊
Oh my...
你想聽個真的笑話嗎
Do you wanna hear a real joke...?
想
Yes.
我老爸就在諾克斯工作
My old man worked at Knox.
是嗎
Yeah?
他在揚克斯市干推銷
He was a salesman in Yonkers.
有一年
Once a year,
他帶我進城吃午飯
He used to take me to the city for lunch.
那本該是個特別的傳道解惑的場合
It was supposed to be a very special, life-advice sort of occasion.
真不錯
Nice.
不
No.
不是的
Not really.
我坐在那兒想
I used to sit there and think.
上帝  我求你別讓我像他那樣庸碌一生
"I hope to Christ I don't end up like you."
現在  我坐在這兒
Now here I am,
一個30歲的諾克斯職員
A thirty year old Knox man.
你能有什麼法子
Can you beat that?
我想我沒太注意...
I think I kind of lost you...
你爸爸以前在諾克斯工作?
Your father worked for Knox...?
抱歉  我有點兒...
I'm sorry. Everything's kinda...
不能集中精神
...going out of focus
我們出去走走吧
Why don't we get some air?
我們倆
You with me
這是你嗎
Is this you?
是啊
Yeah.
你去過巴黎嗎
You've been to Paris?
我哪兒都沒去過
I've never really been anywhere.
那我該帶你去一次
Maybe I'll take you with me then.
只要有機會我就會回去的
I'm going back first chance I get.
我跟你說
I tell you.
那兒的人都朝氣蓬勃
People are alive there.
不像這裡
Not like here.
愛寶  我只知道...
All I know April is...
我想要體驗一切
I wanna feel things.
真真切切地去感受
Really feel them.
明白嗎
You know?
這算得上是野心嗎
How's that for an ambition...?
弗蘭克·惠勒
Frank Wheeler
我覺得  你是我見過的
I think you're the most interesting person
最有趣的男人
I've ever met.
我猜你今早上班時沒想到會這樣吧
Guess this wasn't what you had in mind when you went to work this morning?
是啊  真沒想到
No. It's really wasn't.
你有煙嗎  弗蘭克
Do you have a cigarette, Frank?
當然
Yeah, sure.
給你點上
There you go.
我給你拿點什麼喝的吧
Can I get you a drink or anything?
不  謝了  莫林  有點兒...
No thanks, Maureen. Actually it's...
有點兒晚了  我看...
It's getting kind of late. I guess I...
我看我還是回去了吧
I guess I'd better be cutting out.
天啊  是呀  你錯過火車了吧
Oh. Gee. That's right. Did you miss your train?
沒關係
That's all right.
我搭下一班
I'll catch the next one.
聽著
Listen,
你真的一級棒
You were swell.
再會
Take care now.
弗蘭克...
Frank...
幹嗎打扮得這麼隆重
Why are you all dressed up?
首先
First of all,
我想念你一整天了
I missed you all day
而且  我要道歉
And I wanna say I'm sorry.
從演那齣愚蠢的戲劇以來
I'm sorry for the way I've been since that stupid play.
這些日子  都是我不好
I'm sorry for everything.
我愛你
And I love you.
其它的以後再說
The rest can wait
現在  你...
Now, you...
在這兒等我叫你再進來  好嗎
Just wait here till I call you. Okay?
好
Okay.
好啦  弗蘭克
Alright Frank!
你能進來啦
You can come in now!
祝你生日快樂
"Happy Birthday to you."
親愛的爸爸生日快樂
"Happy Birthday dear Daddy."
祝你生日快樂
"Happy Birthday to you."
生日快樂  親愛的
Happy Birthday, Darling.
我愛你  爸爸
I love you, Daddy.
我也是
I love you too.
弗蘭克
Frank.
我有了個絕妙的主意
I have had the most wonderful idea.
我都想一整天了
I've been thinking about it all day.
是什麼呀  寶貝
Baby, what's all this about?
你知道我們已經攢了多少錢嗎
You know how much money we have saved...?
多到不用你賺一分錢我們就能生活半年
Enough to live on for six months without you earning another dime.
如果賣了房子車子  時間還能更長
And with the money we could get from the house and the car, longer than that.
賣房...
What we get for the house...
親愛的  你這是什麼意思
Sweetheart, what are you talking about?
我們住哪兒去啊
Where are we going to live?
巴黎
Paris.
什麼
What?
你總說那是唯一一處
You always said it was the only place
讓你流連忘返的地方
You'd ever been, that you wanna to go back to.
唯一一處值得生活的地方
The only place that was worth living.
我們為什麼不去呢
So why don't we go there?
你說真的?
You're serious?
是啊
Yes.
有什麼能阻止我們
What's stopping us?
我能想到好多
Well, I can think of a number of different things.
例如  我要找什麼工作
For example, what kind of a job could I possibly get?
你不用找任何工作
You won't be getting any kind of job,
我來
Because I will.
好  好
Oh, right. Right.
不許笑話我
Don't laugh at me.
聽我說完
Listen a minute.
你知道在歐洲
Do you know what they pay
政府機關秘書的薪水嗎
For secretarial positions in the government agencies in Europe?
不知道
No. I don't.
聽著  弗蘭克
Listen Frank,
我是認真的
I'm serious about this.
-你覺得我在開玩笑嗎
-Do you think I'm kidding or something?
-好吧
-Okay.
我只是有幾個問題
I just have a couple of questions, is all.
我想知道  你外出工作賺錢
For one thing, what exactly am I supposed to be doing
那我幹嗎呢
While you're out earning all this money?
你看不出來嗎
Don't you see,
這才是關鍵
That's the whole idea?
你就做7年前沒做成的事
You'll be doing what you should've been allowed to do seven years ago.
你有足夠的時間了
You'll have time.
你有生以來第一次有時間
For the first time in your life you'll have time to find out
去弄明白你到底想要幹什麼
What it is that you actually want to do.
而當你弄明白之後
And when you figure it out,
你有足夠的時間和自由重新開始
You'll have the time and the freedom to start doing it.
親愛的  這根本不切實際
Sweetheart, it's just not very realistic, is all.
不  弗蘭克  現在的生活才不切實際
No, Frank. This is what's unrealistic.
一個有著聰明頭腦的男人
It's unrealistic for a man with
年復一年地做著他根本無法忍受的工作
A fine mind to go on working
居住在自己根本不喜歡的地方
Year after year at a job he can't stand,
而且他的妻子也跟他一樣
Coming home to a place he can't stand,
那才叫不切實際
To a wife who's equally unable to stand the same things.
想要聽最糟的那部分嗎
Do you want to know the worst part?
在一切事物上我們都高人一等
Our whole existence here is based on this great premise
那是我們在這兒生活的最大前提
That we're special and superior to the whole thing.
但我們並沒有
But we're not.
我們跟其他人一樣
We're just like everyone else.
看看我們自己  我們都在自欺欺人
Look at us. We've bought into the same ridiculous delusion.
這個想法使你不得不放棄去追求生活
This idea that you have to resign from life
並因為孩子而安定生活
And settle down the moment you have children.
我們因為它而互相折磨
And we've been punishing each other for it.
聽著  我們決定離開這裡
Listen, we decided to move out here.
沒人逼我去諾克斯工作
No one forced me to take the job at Knox.
誰說我想做番大事業來著
I mean, whoever said I was meant to be a big deal, anyway?
當我第一次遇見你的時候
When I first met you,
這個世界上沒什麼你不能做的
There was nothing in the world you couldn't do or be.
當你第一次遇見我的時候  我是個自作聰明
When you first met me I was a little wise guy
大嘴巴小伙子  僅此而已
With a big mouth, that's all.
不是  你怎麼可以如此貶低自己
You were not. How can you even say that?
好  好  我有大把時間
Okay. Okay, so I'll have time.
天曉得那太吸引人了  太吸引人了
And god knows that's appealing. It's very appealing.
你所說的一切都很在理
And everything you're saying makes sense
如果我確實有才華
If I had a definite talent,
如果我是位作家或是位藝術家
If I were a writer or an artist.
不  但是  弗蘭克  聽著  聽我說
No. But, Frank, listen. Listen to me.
你的才華都被掩埋了
It's what you are that's being stifled.
被這樣的生活拒之門外了
It's what you are that's being denied and denied in this kind of life.
那是什麼
And what's that?
你不知道嗎
Don't you know?
你是這個世界上最美妙絕倫的人
You're the most beautiful and wonderful thing in the world.
你是個大丈夫
You're a man.
機不可失  失不再來  弗蘭克
This is our chance, Frank. This is our one chance.
好
Okay.
你答應了?
Okay?
還有什麼可拒絕的呢
Why not? Why the hell not?
-大家早安  -早啊  弗蘭克
-Good morning, all. -Morning, Frank.
弗蘭克林  很高興見到你春風滿面的
Franklin. Good to see your shining face.
-有什麼好事嗎  -夥計們  我要移居巴黎了
-What's the news? -Fellas, I'm moving to Paris.
是嗎  我也要移居丹吉爾了
Indeed. And I'm moving to Tangiers.
發往托萊多的公司內部電函
Intra-company letter to Toledo.
注意  給分公司經理  B.F.查默斯
Attention B.F. Chalmers, branch manager.
關於最近反覆地函件往來
With regard to recent and repeated correspondence,
這次發函通知問題
This is to advise that the matter has been
將會圓滿解決  句號
Very satisfactorily taken in hand, period.
另起一行
Paragraph.
我們完全同意現有的公司簡介並不合適
We wholly agree that the existing brochure is unsuitable.
到最後  我們已改進  引用一句話
To this end, we have developed, quote,
"談及生產調度"
"Speaking of production control."
給  惠勒太太  這些是您要的旅行支票
Here you go, Mrs Wheeler. These are the traveller's cheques you requested.
-好的  -您預定的船票
-Yes. -Your steamer reservations.
我會幫您把這些遞交給大使館
These I'll pass on to the embassy for you.
-祝您好運  -謝謝
-Good luck. -Thank you.
9月份走  最遲10月份
September. October at the outside.
我開始想像人們隨心所欲地
I just happen to think people are better off
做著自己確實喜歡的工作
Doing some kind of work they actually like.
-是啊  是啊  -絕對是...
-Right. Right, yes. -Absolutely, absolutely.
但是  如果這兒有份真正適合你的工作在等著你
But, I mean, assuming there is this true vocation waiting for you,
你不會在這兒發掘嗎
Wouldn't you be just as likely to discover it here as there?
我不認為在諾克斯大廈15層
I don't think it's possible to discover anything
能發掘什麼東西
On the 15th floor of the Knox building,
你們也一樣
And I don't think any of you do either.
爸爸  爸爸  爸爸
Daddy, Daddy, Daddy!
-邁克爾  -爸爸  你會給我們講故事嗎...
-Michael. -Daddy, will you read us...
...直奔這兒
...all the way to here.
我們得搭乘一艘大船穿越海洋抵達那兒
We have to take a big boat ride across the sea to get there.
-但那兒我一個人都不認識  -我知道  我也是啊
-But I won't know anybody there. -I know. I know. Neither will I.
但你剛上學的時候不也一樣嗎
But remember how you felt when you started school?
看看現在你有那麼多朋友了
And now look how many friends you have.
你們絕對猜不到巴黎人都吃什麼
You'll never guess what they eat in Paris.
-你們絕對猜不到  -吃什麼
-You'll never guess. -What?
-吃黏黏的蝸牛  -蝸牛?
-Slimy Snails. -Snails?
黏黏的蝸牛和青蛙腿
Slimy snails and icky frog's legs.
米莉  你在哪兒  寶貝
Milly, where are you, doll?
快點換衣服  他們馬上就到了
You better get changed, they'll be here soon.
-你就穿這身衣服嗎  -你不喜歡嗎
-Is that what you're wearing? -Don't you like it?
不  不  你看起來漂亮極了  寶貝
Yeah, yeah. You look great, doll.
我得快點去換好衣服
Guess I better haul ass.
小伙子們  你們好啊
Hiya, gang.
你們在看什麼呢
What you watching?
謝普?
Shep?
我到處找你呢
I was calling you and calling you.
來啦  小點心來啦
Here we go. Just a little something.
-看起來美味極了  餓死了  -愛寶  我可猜不透
-Those look great. I'm starving. -April, I can't get over it,
你看起來像吃了金絲雀的貓
You look like the cat that ate the canary.
有什麼事要宣佈嗎  有什麼小道消息嗎
Do you have something to tell us? just a little bit of news?
米莉  其實  我們...我們確實有些重要的事要宣佈
Well, actually, Milly, we...Well, we do have some important news, yes.
我就知道
I knew it.
親愛的  你來宣佈吧  講吧
Honey, why don't you tell them? Go ahead.
我們要去歐洲了  去巴黎
We're going to Europe. To Paris.
去定居
To live.
-什麼  -什麼時候
-What? -When?
-9月份走  -為什麼
-In september. -But what for?
為什麼  因為我們一直都嚮往去那兒
What for? Well, because we've always wanted to.
因為孩子還小  因為那兒漂亮
Because the kids are young enough. Because it's beautiful.
我是說真的  謝普  你去過那兒  你跟她講講吧
I mean, really. Shep, you've been there, you tell her.
-對  是個不錯的城市  -對
-Yeah, it's a great city. -Yeah.
你們什麼時候做的決定
When did you make this decision?
大概一週前吧  記不清楚了
About a week ago? It's hard to remember.
我們突然決定的  僅此而已
We just suddenly decided to go, that's all.
大概一週前決定的  你們現在才說
About a week ago, you tell us now.
我們得深思熟慮過後才告訴你們
We had to get used to the idea.
那都安排好了嗎  弗蘭克  在那兒找工作還是怎樣
So, what's the deal, Frank? You get a job over there, or what?
-不  還不大確定  -不大確定?
-No, no. Not exactly. -What do you mean, "not exactly"?
弗蘭克不會找任何工作  因為我會去工作
Frank won't be getting any kind of a job, because I will.
那你打算做什麼呢  弗蘭克
So what are you going to do,Frank?
我要去進修  去讀書
I'm going to study. And I'm going to read.
我想我終於要弄清在接下來的人生中我想要做什麼了
I suppose I'm going to finally figure out what I want to do with my life,
謝普
Shep.
那她支持你嗎
While she supports you?
當然  她很支持我
Yes. While she supports me.
一開始就支持我
In the beginning.
那邊的政府機構付給秘書的薪酬
You wouldn't believe what they pay for secretarial work
令人難以置信
In those government agencies over there.
像北約和非洲經濟委員會那些機構
NATO and ECA and those places.
而且那邊的生活費用超低的  對吧
And the cost of living is dirt cheap, right?
超低
It's so cheap.
其實我們只是需要換換環境罷了
The truth is we just need something different.
歲月催人老  我們不想生命白白流逝
We're not getting any younger and we don't want life to just pass us by.
是啊
That's right.
聽起來棒極了  年輕人
Gee, it sounds wonderful, kids.
我說真的  聽起來真的很棒
I mean it. It really sounds wonderful.
-謝謝  米莉  -米莉
-Thank you, Milly. -Oh, Milly.
我們一定會想你們的  對吧  親愛的  天哪
We'll certainly miss you both. Won't we, sweetie? Golly.
-當然  -我們也會想你們的
-Sure. -We'll miss you, too.
-一定會  -一定
-Of course. -True.
我們應該為去巴黎乾一杯
We should have a toast or something. To Paris.
-為巴黎乾杯  -為巴黎乾杯
-To Paris. -To Paris.
為巴黎乾杯
To paris.
-乾杯  -乾杯
-Cheers. -Cheers.
你知道我在想什麼嗎
You know what I think?
什麼
What?
我認為這整個計劃聽起來有點不成熟
I think this whole plan sounds a little immature.
天哪  我放心多了
Oh, god, I am so relieved.
我也是  我也一直那麼想
Me, too. I was thinking that the whole time.
我的意思是  什麼樣的男人會整天坐在家裡
I mean, what kind of man is going to sit around
游手好閒  無所事事
In his bathrobe all day picking his nose
-而老婆卻在外面賺錢養家呢
-While his wife goes out and works?
-不知道
-I don't know, Shep.
我也不知道
I just don't know.
你幹嗎哭啊
Why are you crying?
怎麼了
What's the matter?
沒什麼  我只是要發洩一下罷了
It's nothing. I'm just so relieved.
謝普
Shep.
求你別哭了  沒事的  一切都會過去的
Don't cry. Please. It's all right. Everything's going to be all right.
我的天哪  瞧他們當時的臉  天哪
My god, their faces! Oh, god.
天哪
Oh, god!
愛寶  坦白講  你知道這像什麼嗎
You know what this is like, April, honestly?
這麼講吧
Just talking like this?
去歐洲的這個想法
The whole idea of going off to Europe this way?
在戰亂之中  這是我第一次感到要去實現夢想
This is the way I felt going up to the line the first time, in the war.
曾經  我大概跟別人一樣也會被嚇到
I mean, I was probably just as scared as everyone else,
但內心我從未感到如此舒暢
But inside I never felt better.
我感到自己還活著  熱血沸騰  我感到...
I felt alive. I felt full of blood. I felt...
一切都...一切看起來都更真實了
Everything just... everything seemed more real.
大伙穿著制服
The guys in their uniforms.
樹上  田園上  還有我們身上的皚皚白雪
The snow on the fields,the trees, and all of us.
我們這些行人
All of us just walking.
當然  我曾被嚇到了
I mean, I was scared, of course.
但我一直在想像  "就是它  這才是真理"
But I just kept thinking, "This is it, you know. This is the truth."
曾經我也那麼覺得
I felt that way once, too.
什麼時候
When?
你第一次像我示愛的時候
The first time you made love to me.
愛寶
April.
弗蘭克
Frank.
-怎麼了  -巴特·波洛克來了
-What's up? -Bart Pollock's here.
在邦迪的辦公室
He's in Bandy's office.
大事不妙啊
Big deal, huh?
看起來像是要找你談話
Looks like he wants to talk to you.
喂  別提我的大名啊
Hey, keep my name out of it.
很高興見到你  弗蘭克  認識巴特·波洛克吧
Frank. Good to see you. You know Bart Pollock?
-從未見過面  但當然...  -很高興認識你  弗蘭克
-Well, we've never met, but of course... -Good to know you, Frank.
"談及生產調度"
"Speaking of production control"?
弗蘭克  這真是驚世之作啊
Frank, this is a crackerjack.
托萊多的人滿意極了
They are tickled to death in Toledo.
真的嗎
Really?
波洛克這傢伙是品味極差人物的絕佳代表素材
So, this guy Pollock was perfect presidential material in the worst sense.
笑得臉部肌肉都快抽筋了
A million dollar smile and about three pounds of muscle between the ears.
愛寶  你真該聽聽這傢伙說的話
April, you should have heard this guy.
"弗蘭克  這真是驚世之作啊"  馬屁都快拍到馬腿上了
"Frank, this is a crackerjack." What a horse's ass.
真想看看當你告訴他要辭職時  他的臉色啊
Wish I'd seen his face when you told him you were leaving.
他們來了
Here they come.
-抱歉來晚了  -沒事
-Sorry to be late. -You're not late.
-交通大擁堵  -謝謝  何必那麼客氣呢
-The traffic was terrible. -Thank you. You didn't have to do that.
-很高興見到你們  -很糟糕吧  霍華德
-Good to see you. -Wasn't it terrible, Howard?
第12大道
Well, Route 12.
到他們擴路完畢為止
By the time they finish that stretch of road,
他們不得不再重新開始  對吧
They'll have to start all over again, right?
-你一定是約翰吧  -約翰  打個招呼
-And you must be John? -Say hello, John.
很高興見到你  久仰大名
Nice to meet you. Heard a lot about you.
-寶貝孩子們在哪兒呢  -他們去參加生日派對了
-Where are your darling children? -They're at a birthday party.
-抱歉他們沒法在場  -不要緊
-Sorry they couldn't be here. -Don't worry.
如果有個精神病患者來我家
If I had a certified lunatic coming around my house,
我大概也會把孩子們支走
I'd probably get the kids out of the way, too.
瞧你們還弄了吃的  真是太客氣了
Look at all this food. You didn't have to go to any trouble for us.
只是些三明治而已
It's just some sandwiches.
約翰  要吃三明治嗎
John, would you like a sandwich?
幾個月來海倫一直談到你們
Helen's been talking it up about you people for months.
在革命路上年輕友善的惠勒夫婦
The nice young Wheelers on Revolutionary Road,
在惠勒路上年輕友善的革命者們
The nice young revolutionaries on Wheeler Road.
-你們誰要喝雪利酒嗎  -弗蘭克  別麻煩了
-Would anyone like some sherry? -Please don't bother, Frank.
我要點兒
I'd like some sherry.
如果海倫不打我的話  她的那杯也給我
And I'll drink Helen's, too, if she doesn't beat me to it.
但是  你有加冰威士忌嗎
But, hey, you got a high-ball glass?
放兩三塊小方冰進去  斟滿
Put a couple-three ice cubes in it, pour it up to the brim.
-我喜歡這樣喝酒  -我想我能辦到
-That's the way I like it. -I think I can handle that.
愛寶  這個雞蛋沙拉很好吃  你一定要教我怎麼做
This egg salad is delicious, April. You must tell me how you fix it.
-弗蘭克  你是律師?  -不  不  不是
-You a lawyer, Frank? -No. No, I'm not.
我曾經可能是個律師
I could use a lawyer.
約翰  別又開始講律師的事了
John, let's not get started again about the lawyer.
老爸  你能不能就坐那兒
Pop, couldn't you just sit there
吃你那美味雞蛋沙拉  少摻和
And eat your wonderful egg salad and quit horning in?
我有很多問題要問呢
See, I've got a good many questions to ask
我願意為答案付出代價
And I'm willing to pay for the answers.
現在  我無需被告知一個男人拿著茶几
Now, I don't need to be told that a man who goes after his mother
追逐他母親  會使自己處於法律的劣勢方
With a coffee table is putting himself in a weak position legally,
那太明顯了
That's obvious.
約翰  過來看看窗外的美妙風景
John, come and have a look out this fabulous picture window.
如果他用茶几打她並殺她
If he hits her with it and kills her,
那就是一起刑事案
That's a criminal case.
快看  太陽出來了
Oh, look, the sun's coming out!
如果他只是打碎茶几
If all he does is break the coffee table
還有衝她發火
And give her a certain amount of aggravation
她決定訴諸法庭  那就是民事訴訟案
And she decides to go to court over it, that's a civil case.
也許我們會看到彩虹  約翰  快來看呀
Maybe we'll have a rainbow. John, come have a look.
媽  幫幫忙  閉上你的嘴巴
Ma, how about doing everybody a favour? How about shutting up!
冷靜點
Settle down, now.
也許我可以調查一下  推薦個人  你意下如何
Maybe I can look into it, recommend someone. What do you say?
弗蘭克  你做什麼的
So, what do you do, Frank?
其實我是在諾克斯商業機械公司上班
I work at Knox Business Machines, actually.
設計機械嗎
You design the machines?
-不是  -製造  銷售  還是修理?
-Nope. -Make them, sell them, repair them?
-那麼多問題  -算是銷售人員吧
-All these questions. -I help sell them, I guess.
我在辦公室做事  其實  那是...
I work in the office. Actually, it's...
有點無趣的工作  真的
Well, it's sort of a stupid job, really.
對它根本一點興趣都沒有
There's nothing interesting about it at all.
那為什麼還要做呢
What do you do it for then?
也許弗蘭克不喜歡被質問
Maybe Frank doesn't like being questioned.
好  好...我知道那不關我的事
Okay, okay, okay. I know it's none of my business.
而且  我知道答案
And besides, I know the answer.
你要養家餬口  所以必須工作
You want to play house, you got to have a job.
你想要住很漂亮的房子  很溫馨的房子
You want to play very nice house, very sweet house,
然後你就得接受一份你不喜歡的工作
Then you've got to have a job you don't like.
無論誰過來說"你為什麼工作"
Anyone comes along and says, "what do you do it for?"
他就可能是從州立瘋人院請了4小時假出來的
He's probably on a four-hour pass from the state funny farm.
-都贊同嗎  媽?  -抱歉  弗蘭克
-All agreed? Ma? -Sorry, Frank.
沒事  約翰  說實在的  你剛說的我都贊同
Don't be. Don't be. Actually, John, I agree with everything you just said.
我們都贊同  所以秋天我要離職了  我們要走了
We both do. That's why I'm quitting the job in the fall. We're taking off.
移居巴黎
We're moving to Paris.
老媽  你知道這事嗎
Did you know about this, Ma?
你什麼感覺  年輕友善的惠勒一家...
How do you feel about that, Ma? The nice young Wheelers...
年輕友善的惠勒一家要走了
The nice young Wheelers are taking off.
-約翰  求你了  -別激動  孩子
-John, please. -Steady down, son.
約翰  出去呼吸下新鮮空氣怎麼樣
John. John. How about some fresh air? What do you say?
如果你同意的話?
If that's all right with you?
我不知道這樣行不行...
I don't know if it's such a good idea...
如果約翰想去的話  我覺得沒什麼大礙
If John wants to, I don't see the harm.
-好  -你先請
-Good. -After you.
-聽說你是位數學家  -你聽錯了  一切都已成過去時
-I hear you're a mathematician. -You hear wrong. It's all gone now.
過去時?
All gone?
你知道電擊療法嗎
You know what electrical shock treatments are?
知道  知道
Yes. Yes, I do.
我已經做過37次了
I've had 37.
本該擊掉情感問題
Supposed to jolt out the emotional problems.
-卻只擊掉了數學  -真糟糕
-Just jolted out the mathematics. -How awful.
"真糟糕"?  為什麼  因為數學很有意思嗎
"How awful"? Why, because mathematics is so interesting?
不是  因為電擊肯定很糟糕
No. Because the shocks must be awful and,
糟糕是因為它並沒達到你想要的結果
Because it's awful not to be able to do what it is that you want to do.
我想數學肯定很枯燥乏味
I think mathematics must be dull.
我喜歡你太太  弗蘭克
I like your girl, Frank.
我也是
Me, too.
那像你們這樣的夫婦還有什麼可逃避的呢
So, what do a couple of people like you have to run away from?
-我們不是在逃避  -那為什麼要去巴黎
-We're not running. -So what's in Paris?
-不同的生活方式  -也許我們是在逃避
-A different way of life. -Maybe we are running.
我們在逃避這兒絕望空虛的生活  對吧
We're running from the hopeless emptiness of the whole life here, right?
絕望空虛?
The hopeless emptiness?
你說到點上了  很多人都活在空虛裡
Now you've said it. Plenty of people are on to the emptiness,
但直面絕望真的很需要勇氣
But it takes real guts to see the hopelessness.
他好像是第一個能真正了解
You know, he's the first person
我們在談論什麼的人
Who seemed to know what we were talking about.
是真的  不是嗎  也許我們跟他同類
Yeah. That's true, isn't it? Maybe we are just as crazy as he is.
如果瘋狂跟生活息息相關的話
If being crazy means living life as if it matters,
那麼我不在乎我們是否完全瘋了
Then I don't care if we are completely insane.
你在乎嗎
Do you?
不在乎
No.
我好愛你
I love you so much.
告訴你一些事  弗蘭克  那個特德·邦迪  友善的傢伙
Tell you something, Frank. That Ted Bandy, nice guy.
討喜的傢伙
Real sport.
足以勝任部門經理一職
Good enough department head and all.
但對於這些年他把你的才華隱沒
But I'm a little sore at him for the way he's kept you
我真是感到痛心疾首啊
Under a bushel all these years.
-這地方還好吧  -很好  先生  很好
-This place okay for you? -It's just fine, sir. Just fine.
有一件事讓我很感興趣  弗蘭克  就這一件事而已
One thing interests me, Frank, and one thing only.
賣電腦給美國商人
Selling the electronic computer to the American businessman.
那是我組建一個團隊的原因  聚集像你這樣的人才
That's why I'm assembling a team. Men like you.
不再是以前普通的售貨員了
Not your average salesmen.
這意味著有更豐厚的薪水
It'll mean more money,
而且  說實話  也許需要付出更多的時間
And, I got to be honest, maybe more of a time commitment.
但你會成為那些
But you'll be a part
激動人心的事業的一員  惠勒
Of something exciting, Wheeler.
電腦
Computers.
先生  這聽起來挺有趣
Well, sir, it sounds exciting.
-叫我巴特  -巴特
-Bart. -Bart.
巴特  問你一個問題
Bart, let me ask you a question.
你有沒有想到一位叫厄爾·惠勒的人  揚克斯市的
Do you happen to remember an Earl Wheeler? Out of Yonkers?
-恐怕沒有  是你親戚?  -我爸爸
-Can't say that I do. Relation of yours? -My father.
他在諾克斯做了差不多20年的銷售
He worked as a salesman for Knox for almost 20 years.
厄爾·惠勒
Earl Wheeler.
你也理由會記住他
There's no reason you'd remember him.
我敢肯定他是個好人
Well, I'm sure he was a good man.
聽著巴特  有件事我早該和你說
Listen, Bart, there's something I should have mentioned earlier.
我打算在秋季離開公司
I'm going to be leaving the firm in the fall.
-跳槽嗎  -不  不  不是跳槽
-Another outfit? -No, no, it's not another outfit.
聽著  弗蘭克  是薪水的問題嗎
Now, look, Frank. Is it a question of money?
若是薪水問題的話  那就沒有任何理由
Because if it is, there's no reason
使我們達不成共識...
We can't get together on a satisfactory...
我非常感激  但不是錢的問題
Well, I sure appreciate that, but no, it's not the money.
那是...那是私事
It's... well, it's more of a personal thing.
我希望你能理解
I hope you understand.
私事?
A personal thing?
我明白
I see.
弗蘭克  我父親告訴我
Frank, let me tell you something my father told me.
人生只有幾次機會
A man only gets a couple of chances in life.
如果你不及時把握
If he doesn't grab them by the balls,
不久後便會呆呆坐著
It won't be long before he's sitting around wondering
後悔當時有機會卻沒把握住
How he got to be second rate.
我想也是
I guess so.
所以  拜託  別猶豫了
So, do me a favour. Sleep on it.
和你妻子商量一下
Discuss it with your wife.
因為  說實話  妻子總是
Because let's be honest, where the hell would any of us be
伴隨我們左右的
Without our wives, anyway?
而且  弗蘭克  坦率地說  如果你加入我們
And, Frank, in all sincerity, if you do decide to join us,
我相信你將永遠不會後悔
I believe it'll be a thing you'll never regret.
我還相信另一件事
And I believe something else, too.
我相信這會是對你父親很好的紀念
I believe it'd be a fine memorial to your Dad.
想想吧  弗蘭克  仔細想想
Think about it, Frank. Really think about it.
知道你擁有的一切  逗號
Knowing what you've got, comma,
知道你所求  逗號
Knowing what you need, comma,
知道完成某些事可以不用  破折號
Knowing what you can do without, dash.
存貨控制
That's inventory control.
知道你擁有的一切  逗號
Knowing what you've got, comma,
知道你所求  逗號
Knowing what you need, comma,
知道完成某些事可以不用  破折號
Knowing what you can do without, dash.
存貨控制
That's inventory control.
你好  弗蘭克
Hi, Frank.
在加班?
Working late?
是啊  我快好了
Yeah. I got to dig myself out here.
聽說你要升職了
I heard you were getting promoted.
機會難得
Big shot.
我想你父親肯定為你感到驕傲
I guess your Dad would have been real proud, huh?
是啊  我想也是
Yeah. Yeah, I guess so.
那也許我該請你喝點東西
So maybe I should take you for a drink or something?
就當慶祝一下
You know, celebrate.
好  可以吧
Yeah, maybe.
我去拿東西
I'll just get my things.
我要帶上我的玩具馬車
I'm going to bring my doll carriage
還有我的3只復活節兔子  還有我的長頸鹿
And my three Easter rabbits and my giraffe
還有我所有的玩偶  玩具房  蠟筆...
And all my dolls and my doll house and my crayons...
也許我們可以把玩具房送給艾德林
I thought maybe we'd give the doll house to Madeline.
我不想送給艾德林
I don't want to give the doll house to Madeline.
但我早和你說清楚了
But I already explained to you,
大的東西很難塞進行李
The big things are going to be hard to pack.
但我可以給她娃娃熊
But she can have my bear,
-還有那3只復活節的兔子  -不行  就那大的東西
-And my three easter rabbits. -No! Just the big things.
聽著  為什麼不出去和邁克爾玩兒
Look. Wouldn't you rather go outside and play with Michael?
-我不想去  -你一整天都在房子裡
-I don't feel like it. -You've been inside all day.
我不想出去
I don't feel like it.
我不喜歡向無聊且愚蠢得無法理解的人
Well, I don't feel like explaining everything 15 times
把每一件事情都解釋15遍
To somebody who's too bored and silly to listen!
-好了  愛寶  你怎麼了  -沒事
-All right, April. What's the matter? -Nothing.
我不信  早上發生什麼事了
I don't believe you. Did something happen this morning?
很久以來都沒發生什麼了
Nothing happened today that I haven't known about for days and days.
什麼
What?
天啊  弗蘭克  別再裝傻了
Oh, god, Frank, please don't look so dense.
你就從沒懷疑過?
You mean you haven't guessed or anything?
愛寶  你到底在說什麼
April, what are you talking about?
我懷孕了  就這樣
I'm pregnant, that's all.
什麼
What?
弗蘭克  我本想等孩子們睡了再告訴你的
Frank, I meant to wait till the kids were in bed to tell you,
但我只是...整個星期我都確信
But I just... well, I've been pretty sure all week
今天我去看了醫生
And today I went to the doctor,
現在我根本無法假裝沒事發生
And now I can't even pretend it's not true.
-多久了  -10個星期
-How long? -Ten weeks.
10個星期  10個星期?  你現在才告訴我?
Ten weeks. Ten weeks? And you wait until now to tell me?
我以為...我也不知道我怎麼想的
I thought... I don't know what I thought
對不起  弗蘭克  對不起
I'm sorry, Frank. I'm so sorry.
我知道  我知道你很難過
I know. I know you are. All right?
我們會有辦法的
There are things we can do.
我們不會因此而卻步  對吧
We don't have to let this stop us from going, do we?
記得我告訴你那個學校裡的女孩子嗎
Remember that girl at school I told you about?
只要我們在12個星期前
As long as we take care of it
把它處理掉就沒事了
Before 12 weeks, it's fine.
我們必須同心協力  弗蘭克
We've got to be together in this, Frank.
我們會有辦法的  對嗎
Well, we'll figure it out. All right?
過來
Come here.
12個星期  那我們還有時間來做決定
Twelve weeks. So we have time to decide, right?
對
Right.
我愛你
I love you.
我也愛你
I love you, too.
弗蘭克  工作怎樣了  公司沒你也能運作?
So, Frank, how's work? They gonna survive without you?
事實上  前幾天發生了件很搞笑的事
Actually, something kind of funny happened the other day.
我只是做了點無聊的事
I did some dumb little piece of work
想要逃離邦迪的束縛
To get myself off the hook with Bandy,
突然  我就變成一個前途光明的有位青年了
And suddenly, I'm the bright young man.
-事情總是這樣  不是嗎  -難以置信
-That's always the way, ain't it? -It's incredible.
我是說  我只是用幾分鐘時間搞定那東西
I mean, I knocked this thing off in a couple of minutes
現在他們想我加入他們的精英銷售員隊伍
And now they want me to join their team of "specialist" salesmen.
一群白癡
Morons.
那會很有趣  如果他們
Well, it would be funny if they weren't offering
給我不菲的薪水
So much damn money.
那麼  你被誘惑住了嗎
So, are you tempted?
真有點諷刺  不是嗎
Well, it's just kind of ironic, don't you think?
我以為你已經拒絕了這份工作
I thought you turned the job down.
還沒有
Not yet.
這只是給我一個選擇  就這樣
It's just an option, that's all.
有了這麼多的錢
With the kind of money they're talking,
我們的生活就會有很大改觀了
Things could be different for us here.
我們可以去更好的地方  去旅行
We could get a better place. Travel.
我是說在這兒我們也可以很開心
The point is, we could be happy here,
起碼會有一陣子
At least for a little while.
不可能只有巴黎人
It is possible that Parisians aren't the only ones
才能追求有趣的生活  愛寶
Capable of leading interesting lives, April.
所以你已經作出決定了?
So you've made up your mind?
不  不  就像我之前說的  那只是一個選擇
No. No. Like I said, it's just an option. That's all.
假設你是對的
And supposing you're right.
你去掙這些錢  我們在這兒過著有趣的生活
You make all this money and we have this interesting life here.
每天掙扎在你覺得荒唐的工作裡
Won't you still be wasting your life
那還不是在浪費你的生命嗎
Toiling away at a job you find ridiculous?
你就別管我的事了  好嗎
Maybe we let that be my business, all right?
你的事?
Your business?
這裡太熱了  我去濕濕身子
You know what? It's too hot for this. I'm going to go get wet.
-你不想去  對不對  -別這樣  愛寶  我當然想去
-You don't want to go, do you? -Come on, April. Of course, I do.
不  你不想  因為你從未嘗試過任何事
No, you don't. Because you've never tried at anything.
如果你什麼也不嘗試  你永遠會失敗
And if you don't try at anything, you can't fail.
你什麼意思  我不嘗試?
What the hell do you mean I don't try?
我供養你  是我買下了這房子
I support you, don't I? I pay for this house.
我每天花10小時干我無法忍受的工作
I work 10 hours a day at a job I can't stand.
-你沒必要去做  -狗屁
-You don't have to. -Bullshit!
聽著  我對此也很不爽
Look, I'm not happy about it.
但我有骨氣  不會逃避責任
But I have the backbone not to run away from my responsibilities.
用你的骨氣去追求你想要的生活  弗蘭克
It takes backbone to lead the life you want, Frank.
你要去哪兒
Where are you going?
我要用浴室  這不會影響你吧  愛寶
If it's all right with you, April, I'm gonna go use the bathroom. Okay?
你他媽要用這個幹什麼
What the hell are you going to do with this?
你到底在想什麼
And what do you think you're going to do?
-你要阻止我嗎  -我就是要阻止你
-You're going to stop me? -You're damn right I am!
來啊
Go ahead and try.
聽著  如果你真的做了  愛寶  我發誓我...
Listen to me. You do this, April, you do this and I swear to god I'll...
你怎樣  離開我嗎  是威脅還是承諾?
You'll what? you'll leave me? Is that a threat or a promise?
你什麼時候買的  愛寶
When did you buy this, April?
這東西你買了多久  我要知道
How long have you had this? I want to know!
天啊
Jesus christ.
整件事你真的很荒謬
You really are being melodramatic about this whole thing.
只要在第12週前完成  就完全沒事
As long as it's done in the first 12 weeks, it's perfectly safe.
那就是現在  愛寶  我就沒有發言權嗎
That's now, April! Don't I get a say?
當然有
Of course you do!
我都是為了你  弗蘭克  你難道看不見嗎
It would be for you, Frank. Don't you see?
那樣我們就有時間  就像我們之前說的
So you can have time, just like we talked about.
你的想法快使我吐了
How can it be for me when the thought of it
怎麼會是為我好呢  天啊
Makes my stomach turn over, for God's sake?
那就是我自私好了
Then it's for me.
告訴我  我們能在巴黎要孩子  弗蘭克
Tell me we can have the baby in Paris, Frank.
告訴我  我們會有不同的生活
Tell me we can have a different life.
就是別讓我待在這兒  拜託了
But don't make me stay here. Please.
-我們不能在巴黎要孩子  -為什麼
-We can't have the baby in Paris. -Why not?
我不需要我們擁有的一切  我不在乎住哪兒
I don't need everything we have here. I don't care where we live.
是誰定下這些規矩的?
I mean, who made these rules, anyway?
聽著  我們搬來這兒的唯一原因是我懷孕了
Look, the only reason we moved out here was because I got pregnant.
然後我們又生了一個
Then we had another child
來證明前面一個不是錯誤
To prove the first one wasn't a mistake.
這一切究竟還要持續多久
I mean, how long does it go on?
弗蘭克  你真的想再要一個孩子嗎
Frank. Do you actually want another child?
想嗎  快點  告訴我
Well, do you? Come on, tell me.
告訴我  弗蘭克  記得嗎
Tell me the truth, Frank. Remember that?
我們以前就是這樣挽回面子的
We used to live by it.
你知道這真相有多好嗎
And you know what's so good about the truth?
其實每個人都知道
Everyone knows what it is, however long they've lived without it.
沒人忘記這真相  弗蘭克  他們只是更擅長說謊
No one forgets the truth, Frank. They just get better at lying.
所以告訴我  你真的想再要一個孩子嗎
So tell me, do you really want another child?
我只知道我的感覺
All I know is what I feel.
任何頭腦清醒的人都和我有相同的感受  愛寶
And anyone else in their right mind would feel the same way, April.
但我們已經有兩個小孩了  這還不夠讓我說話嗎
But I've had two children. Doesn't that count in my favour?
天啊  愛寶  你竟然這樣想
Christ, April! The fact that you even put it that way!
你弄得好像
You make it seem as if having
有小孩就是一種懲罰
Children is some sort of a goddamn punishment.
我愛我的孩子  弗蘭克
I love my children, Frank.
你確信?
And you're sure about that, huh?
你到底是什麼意思
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
愛寶  你剛說我們的女兒是個錯誤
April, you just said our daughter was a mistake.
天知道你是否想過要打掉她
How do I know you didn't try to get rid of her,
-或打掉邁克爾  -不
-Or michael for that matter? -No.
天知道你是否想把我們整個家衝進馬桶
How do I know you didn't try to flush our entire fucking family down the toilet
不  那不是真的  我當然沒有
no, that's not true. Of course I didn't.
我怎麼知道  愛寶
But how do I know, April?
停  不要說了  弗蘭克
Stop. Please just stop, Frank.
愛寶  一個普通的女人  一位正常的母親
April, a normal woman, a normal sane mother
絕不會去買橡膠管來給自己墮胎
Doesn't buy a piece of rubber tubing to give herself an abortion
那樣她就能生活在自己的幻想中
So she can live out some kind of a goddamn fantasy.
聽著  整件事你都極不理智
Look, all I'm saying is you don't seem entirely rational about this thing.
我想是時候找個人
And I think it's about time we found somebody
來給你理順生活了
To help make some sense of your life.
用那份工作的薪水來支付這費用?
And the new job's going to pay for that, too?
愛寶  如果你需要心理醫生
April, if you need a shrink,
很明顯
Obviously.
好了  我想我們沒話說了
Okay. I guess there isn't much more to say then, is there?
所以去巴黎是個很幼稚的想法  對吧
So I guess Paris was a pretty childish idea, huh?
也許吧
I guess maybe it was.
愛寶  在這兒我們也能很開心
April, we can be happy here.
我能使你快樂
I can make you happy here.
我們已經在這兒住那麼久了  沒必要離開
We've had a great couple of months. It doesn't need to end.
我們會好起來的  我保證
We're going to be okay. I promise.
希望如此  弗蘭克
I hope so, Frank.
我真的希望如此
I really hope so.
久等了  波洛克先生現在可以見你了
Thank you for waiting. Mr Pollock will see you now.
非常感謝
Thanks so much.
被失敗的避孕打擊啊
Foiled by faulty contraception.
不得不說  我很遺憾
I can't say that I'm sorry.
你只是在那間舊房間迷失了  我可以告訴你
You'd have been sorely missed in the old cubicle, I can tell you that.
你不也一樣嗎
Wouldn't have been the same without you.
而且...
Besides... well...
什麼
What?
那計劃似乎很不現實  不是嗎
The plan always seemed a touch unrealistic, don't you think?
我想這不關我的事
I suppose it's none of my business, really.
當然  這不關你的事
No. No. I suppose it isn't.
他們將在秘書室裡慶祝
They'll be celebrating in the secretarial pool.
記得你第一次帶我們來這裡嗎
Hey! Remember the first time you brought us here?
當然
Absolutely.
你說  維托小木屋的酒品味獨特
You said it takes a special kind of taste to enjoy vito's log cabin.
它味道很糟糕  但又覺得好喝
It's so awful, it's kind of nice.
看看  多開心  我們又聚在一起了
Look at me. I'm just so happy. Our little gang's back together again.
大家喜歡那些樂隊和服務生嗎? 他們今晚是不是很棒?
How do you like the boys in the band? Aren't they swinging tonight?
-歐洲也不怎樣  -沒錯
-Hey, Europe's not going anywhere. -That's right.
愛寶  親愛的  來跳支舞
April, honey, how about a dance?
現在不想  遲會兒吧
Not right now. Maybe later.
-我跳  -好
-I'll dance. -Okay.
我想她還為巴黎感到沮喪  對吧
Guess she's still pretty blue about Paris, huh?
你認為她會好起來嗎
Think she'll be okay?
當然  給我們這些女孩幾天時間
Sure. Give us girls a couple of days
一切就會好起來的
And we can get over anything.
對
Right.
弗蘭克
Frank.
你還好吧  米莉
Are you okay? Are you okay? Milly?
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
太好了
That's just great.
我們該怎樣離開呢
How the hell are we supposed to get out now?
天啊
Oh, boy.
別擔心  謝普  我們可以等一會兒
Don't worry about it, Shep. We can wait. Really.
那保姆該怎麼辦
What about the sitter?
聽著  要不你送米莉回家
Listen, why don't you drive Milly home,
然後你自己回去
Then go home yourself.
這樣就能顧及兩邊的保姆了
That takes care of both sitters.
然後謝普可以遲點送我回去
Then Shep can take me home later.
-這樣不錯  -那好吧
-Yeah, it's fine by me. -Okay, then.
-你...可以嗎  -當然
-You... You'll be all right? -Sure.
好吧
Okay.
-晚安  -晚安
-Good night. -Good night.
希望你能好點
Feel better.
很抱歉你去不了那兒了
I'm sorry you're not going away any more.
我知道這對你很重要
I know it was important to you.
請別誤會  我去過那裡
Don't take this wrong, but I've been there.
他們有的我們都有
They don't have so much we don't have here.
不一定要去巴黎的
It didn't have to be Paris.
你只是想離開這裡  是嗎
You just wanted out, huh?
我想融入這裡
I wanted in.
我只是想讓我們再來一次
I just wanted us to live again.
多少年來  我以為只有我們知道這秘密
For years, I thought we shared this secret.
以為我們會活得很精彩
That we would be wonderful in the world.
但我又不知道具體該怎樣  只是...
I didn't exactly know how, but just...
只是那可能性讓我充滿希望
Just the possibility kept me hoping.
多可憐
How pathetic is that?
多愚蠢
So stupid.
把你所有的希望都寄托於不可能兌現的承諾裡
To put all your hopes in a promise that was never made?
弗蘭克知道  他知道他要什麼
See, Frank knows. He knows what he wants.
他找到了落腳處
He's found his place. He's just fine.
結了婚  有兩個小孩
Married, two kids.
已經足夠了
It should be enough.
滿足了
It is for him.
他是對的
And he's right.
我們並不特別  什麼都不是
We were never special or destined or anything at all.
不  你們很特別
Yes, you are.
你...
You're...
你們是惠勒一家
You're the Wheelers.
你們是很般配的夫妻  所有人都這樣說
You're a terrific couple. Everybody says so.
我看到另一個未來
I saw a whole other future.
我無法放棄
I can't stop seeing it.
不能離開
Can't leave,
不能留下
Can't stay.
對別人毫無用處
No damn use to anyone.
別這樣
Come on.
跳舞吧
Let's do it.
我們去哪兒
Let me take you somewhere.
不  就在這兒  快
No. Just do it here. Now.
愛寶
April.
這是我一直所嚮往的
This is what I've always wanted.
我愛你
I love you.
別說了
Don't say that.
不  我說真的  我愛你
No. I mean it, I love you.
安靜一會兒吧
Please, just be quiet for a minute.
然後載我回家
Then you can take me home.
外面天氣不錯
It's beautiful out.
是啊
Yes, it is.
知道今天是什麼日子嗎
You know what today is?
-第12週了  -是啊
-It's 12 weeks. -That's right.
這個夏天過得有點不太現實
Look, this has been kind of a crazy summer.
我們倆都太緊張了
We've both been under a strain.
我是說  我理解你為什麼煩躁
I mean, I understand why you're upset.
你想知道為什麼我不和你睡一張床了
You know I'm not sleeping with you, and you want to know why.
對不起  弗蘭克  但我不想談這件事
Well, I'm sorry, Frank, but I really don't feel like talking about it.
好吧  那我們談什麼  愛寶
All right. Then what should we talk about, April?
就不能什麼都不談嗎
Would it be all right if we didn't talk about anything?
我們能不能安安靜靜的過日子
I mean, can't we just take each day as it comes, and do the best we can,
而不是老要談那些破事
And not feel like we have to talk about everything all the time?
我沒要建議談那些破事
I don't think I'm suggesting that we talk about everything all the time.
我是說  我們之前都太緊張了
Look, my point is we've both been under a strain
我們應該互相幫對方一把  別再越陷越深了
And we ought to be helping each other out as much as we can right now.
天知道為什麼我最近表現那麼不正常
I mean, god knows my own behaviour has been pretty weird lately.
實際上  我有件事要告訴你
As a matter of fact, there is something I'd like to tell you about.
我在城裡的時候  和一個女人有過幾次...
I've been with a girl a few times, in the city.
我和她都不太熟
A girl I hardly even know.
她對我來說什麼都不是
It was nothing to me,
現在結束了  徹底結束了
But it's over now, really over.
我要是沒結束
And if I weren't sure of that,
就永遠沒法告訴你
I guess I could never have told you about it.
為什麼
Why did you?
寶貝  我不知道
Baby, I don't know.
自從墮胎那件事之後
I think it's a simple case of wanting to be a man again
我只是想找些新鮮的感覺
After all that abortion business.
我有點不理智  總想去證明些什麼
Some kind of neurotic, irrational need to prove something.
不是  我不是問你為什麼告訴我外面有女人
No. I don't mean why did you have the girl.
我是問你為什麼告訴我
I mean, why did you tell me about it?
-你什麼意思  -你告訴我這些幹什麼
-What do you mean? -I mean, what's the point?
是想讓我吃醋嗎
Is it supposed to make me jealous or something?
還是想讓我愛上你
Is it supposed to make me fall in love with you,
還是想讓我和你上睡  還是怎麼的
Or back into bed with you, or what?
你想讓我說什麼  弗蘭克
I mean, what would you like me to say, Frank?
說說你的感受  愛寶
Why don't you say what you feel, April?
我沒感覺
I don't feel anything.
也就是說  你不在乎我做了什麼  我幹了誰是嗎
In other words, you don't care what I do or who I fuck or anything?
對  我想是的  我不在乎
No, I guess that's right. I don't.
愛干誰幹誰吧
Fuck who you like.
愛寶  你不明白我想讓你在乎嗎
April, don't you understand that I want you to care?
我知道  我知道你想
I know. I know you do.
我如果還愛你的話我就會在乎了
And I suppose I would if I loved you.
不過我不愛你了  我剛剛才發現
But I don't think I do any more. And I only just figured that out.
所以我寧願現在什麼都不談
And that's why I'd just as soon not do any talking right now.
少跟我說這些狗屁  少這麼跟我說話
Don't give me that shit, April. Don't give me that.
-你很清楚你愛我  -你這麼覺得嗎
-You know goddamn well you love me. -You think so?
你知道的
You know goddamn well!
有人在家嗎
Anyone home?
不好意思  晚餐有些遲了  再喝點什麼嗎
I'm sorry dinner's late. Would anyone like another drink?
別費心了  坐下聊聊天挺好的
Don't worry. It's nice to just sit a bit and socialise.
不用麻煩了
You shouldn't have gone to all this trouble.
你還要收拾東西呢
With all your packing and whatnot.
我猜你肯定有的忙了  沒別的意思
I imagine you have a lot on your plate. No pun intended.
事實上  有點小變動
Actually, there's been a change of plans.
很顯然啊
I thought maybe it was obvious.
愛寶懷孕了
April here is pregnant.
-恭喜啊  -愛寶
-Congratulations. -oh, April!
我真替你高興
I can't tell you how pleased I am!
我猜你們得需要個大點兒的房子了  是吧
But I expect you'll be needing a bigger house now, won't you?
等等  老媽  等等
Hold it a second, Ma. Hold on a second, Ma.
我沒明白  為什麼很顯然
I don't get this. I mean, what's so obvious about it?
我是說  她懷孕了又怎樣  歐洲人不生孩子嗎
I mean, okay, she's pregnant, so what? Don't people have babies in Europe?
-約翰...  -這麼說吧
-John... -Suppose we just say
哪個地方的人都是這樣  除非能養得起
That people anywhere aren't very well advised to have babies
否則他們不會考慮要孩子的
Unless they can afford them.
好吧  好吧  是錢的問題  錢是個好借口
Okay. Okay, it's a question of money. Money's a good reason.
但是一般都不是真正的原因
But it's hardly ever the real reason.
真正的原因是什麼  老婆不想去了嗎
What's the real reason? Wife talk you out of it or what?
小女人覺得她還沒準備好離開"過家家"的生活
Little woman decide she isn't quite ready to quit playing house?
不是這個原因  我能看出來
No, no, that's not it. I can tell.
她看起來夠強硬
She looks too tough and adequate as hell.
那就是你了  你怎麼了
Okay, then. It must've been you. What happened?
-約翰  別這樣  你太無禮了  -不  不  怎麼了  弗蘭克
-John, please. You're being very rude. -No, no. What happened, Frank?
臨陣畏縮了嗎
You get cold feet?
你還是覺得在這兒好  是嗎
You decide you're better off here after all?
你發現留在這個
You figure it's more comfy
腐朽無望的空虛裡更舒服是嗎
Here in the old hopeless emptiness after all, huh?
就是這麼回事  看他這張臉
Oh, wow, that did it. Look at his face.
怎麼了啊  惠勒  我愈加激昂了嗎
What's the matter, Wheeler? Am I getting warm?
-行了  小子  我覺得我們應該...  -你知道嗎
-All right, son. I think we'd better be... -You know something?
如果他故意讓她中招  我不會感到驚訝的
I wouldn't be surprised if he knocked her up on purpose
這樣他後半生就可以
Just so he could spend the rest of
藏在她的孕婦裝後面了
His life hiding behind a maternity dress.
這樣他就永遠不用去尋找真正的自己了
That way he'd never have to find out what he's really made of.
你給我聽著  我對你已經仁至義盡了
Now look, I think that's just about enough out of you.
你他媽以為你是誰
I mean, who the hell do you think you are?
你來到我家  還說了那麼多
You come in here and say
你腦中那些瘋話
Whatever crazy goddamn thing comes into your head,
我覺得是時候該有人站出來
And I think it's about time somebody
告訴你應該閉嘴了
Told you to keep your goddamn mouth shut.
-他有病  弗蘭克  -有病個屁
-He's not well, Frank. -Not well, my ass!
我才不在乎他是否有病  是死是活
I don't give a damn if he's sick or well or dead or alive,
他應該閉上他那張爛嘴
He should keep his fucking opinions
回到那個他應該待的瘋人院去
In the fucking insane asylum where they belong!
-走吧  孩子  -走吧  約翰
-Let's go, son. -Come on, John.
你男人可真是個大人物  愛寶
Big man you got there, April.
厲害的居家男人
Big family man.
我為你感到遺憾
I feel sorry for you.
還有  你們倆挺配的
Still, maybe you deserve each other.
看你現在這樣子  我也開始為他
I mean, the way you look right now, I'm beginning to feel sorry for him,
感到遺憾了
Too.
你肯定也沒讓他有好日子過
You must give him a pretty bad time
要不為什麼讓孩子來證明他有種
If making babies is the only way he can prove he's got a pair of balls.
-你他媽的...  -他是個病人  弗蘭克
-You fucking... -No! He's not well, Frank!
好了  約翰  快走吧
All right, John. Let's get on out to the car now.
愛寶  太抱歉了  對不起
April, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
是啊  對不起  對不起
Oh, right. Sorry. Sorry! Sorry!
老媽  我說的對不起還不夠多嗎
Ma, have I said "I'm sorry" enough times?
媽的  我是對不起
Damn! I am sorry, too.
我打賭我才是那個最該被抱歉的雜種
I bet I'm just about the sorriest bastard I know.
但是話說回來
But get right down to it,
我也沒有什麼事可開心的
I don't have a whole hell of a lot to be glad about.
是吧
Do I?
但是你知道嗎
But, hey, you know what?
我很為一件事開心
I am glad about one thing.
你知道是什麼嗎
You want to know what I'm glad about?
我很開心我不是那個孩子
I'm glad I'm not gonna be that kid.
好  好  別告訴我
Okay, okay, don't tell me.
別告訴我  我猜猜
Don't tell me, let me guess.
我做了一件讓人很反感的事  對吧
I made a disgusting spectacle of myself, right?
對
Right.
那瘋子說的一切都是對的  是吧
And everything that man said is true, right?
那就是你想說的話嗎
Is that what you're going to say?
很明顯我不用說了
Apparently I don't have to.
-你都替我說了  -你錯了  愛寶
-You're saying it for me. -Well, you're wrong, April.
-是嗎  為什麼我錯了  -因為他是瘋子
-Really? Why am I wrong? -Because the man is insane.
他瘋了  你明白精神錯亂是什麼意思嗎
He's fucking insane! Do you know what the definition of insanity is?
不  你明白嗎
No. Do you?
我明白  就是沒有能力對另一個人負責
Yes, it's the inability to relate to another human being.
沒有能力去愛
It's the inability to love.
愛寶  愛寶
April. April.
April! April!
沒有能力...沒有能力去愛了
The inability... the inability to love.
弗蘭克  你可真是個大話家
Frank. You really are a wonderful talker.
如果單憑說話就可以顛倒是非
If black could be made into white by talking,
你就是最適合這個工作的人
You'd be the man for the job.
現在我瘋了  是因為我不愛你了  對吧
So now I'm crazy because I don't love you. Right?
-你是這個意思吧  -不是
-Is that the point? -No. Wrong.
你瘋了  但你還愛我  這是我的意思  愛寶
You're not crazy and you do love me. That's the point, April.
我不愛你  我恨你
But I don't. I hate you.
你只不過是個在派對上曾逗我笑過的男人
You were just some boy who made me laugh at a party once
而現在我一見你就噁心
And now I loathe the sight of you.
還有  如果你敢靠近我  如果你敢碰我一下
In fact, if you come any closer, if you touch me or anything,
我會大叫的
I think I'll scream.
別這樣  愛寶
Come on. Stop this, April.
去你媽的  愛寶
Fuck you, April!
去你媽的  還有你所有的憎恨  下賤的...
Fuck you and all your hateful, snotty little...
你想幹什麼  想打我嗎
What're you going to do now? Are you going to hit me?
-向我證明你有多愛我?  -別擔心  我都懶得打你
-To show me how much you love me? -Don't worry, I can't be bothered!
你根本都不值得我去打
You're not worth the trouble it would take to hit you.
你都不值得費那些炸彈炸掉你的那些炮灰
You're not worth the powder it would take to blow you up.
你這個空虛  沒有心腸的女人
You're an empty, empty, hollow shell of a woman!
你如果這麼恨我  留在我家幹什麼
What the hell are you doing in my house if you hate me so much?
為什麼還和我結婚
Why the hell are you married to me?
為什麼還懷我的孩子
What the hell are you doing carrying my child?
為什麼你有機會的時候不離開我
I mean, why didn't you just get rid of it when you had the chance?
因為聽我說  聽我說  我有話要告訴你
Because listen to me. Listen to me, I got news for you.
我真希望你離開了我
I wish to god that you had.
愛寶
April!
-愛寶  -離我遠點
-April! -Stay away from me.
-愛寶
-April,
聽著  -離我遠點
listen. -Stay away from me.
難道我在這破林子裡都甩不開你嗎
Can't I even get away from you in the fucking woods?
愛寶  聽著  我不是有心的
April, listen, I didn't mean that.
-真的  我真不是那麼想的  -你能不能閉嘴
-Honestly, I didn't mean what I said. -Are you still talking?
怎樣才能讓你閉嘴?
Isn't there any way to stop your talking?
我想靜一靜  你看不出來嗎  我要安靜
I need to think. Can't you see that? I need to think.
回家吧  你在這幹嗎  愛寶
Please come back to the house. What're you doing out here, April?
你還想讓我再叫嗎  弗蘭克
Do you want me to scream again, Frank?
我會的  我真的會的
Because I will! I mean it!
好吧  好
Okay. Okay.
早
Good morning.
雞蛋要炒的還是煎的
Would you like scrambled eggs or fried?
不知道
I don't know.
什麼都行  炒的吧  能簡單點吧
It doesn't really matter. Scrambled, I guess, if it's easy.
好吧  那我也要炒的
Fine. I'll have scrambled, too.
早餐要是沒有孩子們吵還挺好的  是吧
It's kind of nice having breakfast without the kids for a change, huh?
是啊
Yes.
我想你今天會想要好好吃頓早餐
I thought you'd probably want a good breakfast today.
今天很重要  是吧
I mean, it's kind of an important day for you, isn't it?
你是要今天和波洛克見面嗎
Isn't this the day you have your conference with Pollock?
對啊  對
Yes. Yes, that's right.
-要事啊  -我想也應該很重要
-Big deal. -I imagine it is a pretty big deal.
對他們來說很重要
For them, anyway.
新的工作要做什麼
What exactly do you think you'll be doing in your new job?
你還沒怎麼跟我說過呢
You haven't really told me much about it.
沒有嗎
Haven't I?
其實就是諾克斯準備要
Well, I think this whole thing is about Knox getting ready
買一台大型的計算機
To buy up one of those really big computers,
比500還大的
Even bigger than the 500.
-我沒跟你說過嗎  -沒有
-Didn't I tell you about that? -No.
現在說說
Why don't you tell me now?
基本上  是個很大  很快的算數計算機
You know, basically it's just a big, fast adding machine.
但是你看不到機械部分
Only, instead of mechanical parts, you see,
你能看到上千個獨立電子管
You've got thousands of individual vacuum tubes.
這樣啊
I see.
至少我覺得我明白了
At least I think I see.
是挺有意思的
Yes, it's really kind of interesting, isn't it?
不知道
Well, I don't know.
某些方面來說  是挺有意思的
Yeah, I guess it is kind of interesting, in a way.
要珍惜你做的工作  弗蘭克
You should value what you do, Frank.
顯然你很擅長這個
You're obviously good at it.
我該走了
Well, I guess I'd better be getting started, huh?
我想說  愛寶...
Listen, though, April, the...
這樣多好
This was really nice.
早餐很好  我...
I mean, it was a swell breakfast. Really, I...
我不知道是否有過比這更好的早餐
I don't know when I've ever had a nicer breakfast.
謝謝  我也很開心
Thank you. I enjoyed it, too.
你不再恨我了嗎
Then you don't... you don't hate me or anything?
不  當然不恨了
No. No, of course I don't.
過得愉快
Have a good day.
好吧  再見
Okay, then. So long.
喂?  米莉  還好嗎
Hello. Milly? Everything all right?
沒有  我還是不太舒服
Well, no, I'm afraid I'm not feeling any better.
所以我打個電話
That's really why I called.
如果方便的話  今晚最好了
If it's not an inconvenience for you, this evening would be great.
什麼
What?
不  不  他們要是在外面玩的話就不用了
Oh, no. No. Not if they're outdoors playing.
別把他們叫進來
Don't call them in.
替我親他們一下
Just give them each a kiss for me,
告訴他們...
And tell them I...
Tell them...
你知道的  好的  謝謝  米莉  再見
You know. All right. All right. Thank you, Milly. Bye.
我需要幫助
I think I need help.
革命路115號
115 Revolutionary Road.
-弗蘭克  怎麼回事  -上帝啊
-Frank. They tell you what happened? -Jesus christ.
謝普  他說的我都沒怎麼聽懂
Shep, I didn't understand half the things he told me.
他說她到醫院之前孩子已經沒了
He said the foetus was out before they got her here.
他們得做手術拿出那個  那個什麼
And they had to operate to take out the, what do you call it,
胎盤嗎
The placenta?
她現在大出血
And now she's still bleeding.
他說救護車到之前她就流了很多血
He said that she'd lost a lot of blood before the ambulance came,
他們正在努力止血
And now they're trying to stop it.
他說了一堆我根本聽不懂  什麼毛細血管...
He said a whole lot of things I didn't understand about capillaries...
他說她還在昏迷中  天啊
He said that she's unconscious. Jesus.
弗蘭克  坐下來吧
Okay, Frank, why don't you just take a seat?
我坐下有什麼用  上帝啊
What the hell do I want to sit down for, for god's sake?
好了  弗蘭克  放輕鬆點  冷靜點
Okay, Frank. Just take it easy. Take it easy.
-弗蘭克  我這兒有煙  -她故意的  謝普
-Frank, have a cigarette. -She did it to herself, Shep.
她故意的
She did it to herself.
我給你拿點咖啡
I'm gonna get you some coffee.
他們是那麼好的人  對吧  謝普
They were such wonderful people. Weren't they, Shep?
真的很讓人震驚  可憐的愛寶
It's just devastating. Poor April.
謝謝
Thank you.
弗蘭克現在住在城裡  他在哪兒工作來著
Frank lives in the city now. Where is it that he works?
-巴特·波洛克聯合公司  -計算機的?
-Bart Pollock Associates. -Computers?
有趣的公司
Interesting firm.
-之後再見過他嗎  -沒有  沒再回來過
-Have you seen him since? -No. Not back here.
我想可能是這裡有太多回憶了  謝普在城裡見過他
There are too many memories, I think. Shep has seen him in the city.
是嗎  親愛的
Haven't you, sweetie?
弗蘭克把所有精力都投入到孩子身上
Frank is just devoted to those kids.
只要一有時間  就陪他們玩
Every spare moment he has, he spends with them.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
怎麼了
You all right?
我不想再談惠勒家的事了
I don't want to talk about the Wheelers any more.
好吧
Okay.
我們不說了
We don't have to.
不說了
爸爸  爸爸  看啊  爸爸
Daddy, Daddy, watch. Watch, Daddy.
你不知道我有多喜歡
I can't tell you how pleased I am
革命路的那所小房子  霍華德
About the little revolutionary road place, Howard.
無論我什麼時候經過  都有一種
And now whenever I drive past, it gives me such a lift
想再看看那種清新的氣氛  那種潔淨的感覺
To see it all perked up and spanking clean again.
每戶窗裡都亮著燈
All the lights in all the windows.
你知道嗎
And do you know?
我在想  我喜歡那座房子這麼多年
I was just thinking, I've loved that little house for years.
佈雷斯家是我找的唯一真正適合的人家
And the Braces are the only really suitable people I've ever found for it.
非常好  非常隨和的人家
Really nice, congenial people, I mean.
你是說除了惠勒家之外嗎
Well, except for the Wheelers, you mean.
我曾經非常喜歡惠勒一家
I was very fond of the Wheelers.
我只是感覺他們有點古怪  有點神經質
They were a bit whimsical for my taste. A bit neurotic.
我從沒說過這個  但是他們總是
I never stressed it, but they were often
在有些方面上很難相處
Very trying people to deal with, in many ways.
實際上  那所小房子之所以這麼難賣
And actually, the main reason that the little house was so hard to sell
就是因為他們太不好好愛護這房子了
Was because they let it depreciate so dreadfully.
變形的窗框  潮濕的地窖  滿牆的蠟筆畫
Warped window frames, wet cellar, crayon marks all over the walls,